Okay, in this section we're going to be
covering some basic quality theories.
There's just some quality
theorists that we need
to talk about that you
need to know for the exam.
And you just need to
know these names just at a
very, very high level,
just a very, very high level.
Alright, so we're just going to be talking
about some quality pioneers here and just
a few quality pioneers that you are
expected to know for the PMP exam.
Again, you don't need to know about any of
these people in any of these people in any
kind of any amount
of detail, you just need
to know them at a very, very high level.
All right, so let's talk about this person
here first, Philip Crosby, Phil Crosby.
So he wrote several
books, but one of his most
famous book was something
called Quality is Free.
And he had this notion, the idea that a
company that has a good quality process in
place is going to see savings
in the back end, that's going
to more than offset the
cost of that initial investment.
Building quality into an organization,
it's not cheap.
It is going to cost, it's going to cost
money.
It's a big investment.
However, if you have a
good quality process in place,
you're going to get all
of that investment back.
At the back end, you're going to get it
all back.
And you're going to get it back in the
form of increased productivity,
decreased rework and customer
satisfaction.
I'd say a customer's going to buy more of
your product.
They're going to recommend your product.
You're going to have brand loyalty and so
and so forth.
So in effect, since you're
getting all that money
back, then quality really
should be seen as being free.
And he promoted this concept of zero
defects.
Now, zero defects does not mean 100%
quality control testing.
No, on the contrary, what he was saying
and other quality pioneers as well,
They're saying quality control should be
at a minimum.
Call to control means testing the product.
If you are focusing on quality control,
then that is also an expensive approach
because quality control means building the
product, testing it to see if it works.
If it doesn't work, we go back and fix it.
What a bear approach is, is making sure
that it's built right in the first place,
not focusing on quality control.
Now, neither of them,
or rather, no quality
pioneer is saying
eliminate quality control.
No, you can't eliminate it, but it
shouldn't be focused.
Your focus shouldn't be on quality
control.
Your focus should be
on preventive actions,
and your focus should be on the process.
So this zero defects is basically
talking about the process,
making sure that the
procedures are working correctly.
So the output of each process is
defect-free.
So we're removing all defects and issues
from the actual process itself.
I'm focusing on prevention rather than
inspection.
Inspection basically means testing,
which is quality control.
Then we have Joseph Joran, who we
mentioned very briefly in an earlier video.
Joseph Joran then, he defined quality.
He had a definition of quality.
which included this term here,
fitness for use.
This product, is it fit for the customer's
use?
And he had several criteria, but the one
that you need to know for the exam is this
one here, quality versus grade,
one that we covered in an earlier video.
So again, remember, quality is, does
a product do what it's supposed to do?
Grade refers to the number of features,
the type of features, customer perception,
Right.
You may have a high grade product.
It has all the bells and whistles, all of
these, you know, all
these different features.
But if it keeps breaking down,
then that's poor quality.
So what Joseph Geran
was referring to in this
case, again, we're just
talking very high level.
Your product has to have the minimum
number of features.
If it doesn't have the minimum features,
no one's going to be interested.
But also be careful.
Don't go over the top.
As you add more and more features,
to a particular product that's going to
increase the grade of the product but
that's also going to have more number of
features for things or there's more number
of things to break down that's poor
quality right so just having a whole bunch
of features that keeps breaking down is no
good your focus should be on quality
rather than on grade now a couple of other
people here we have Deming, Edward Deming,
right?
So he developed what's
known as the 14 points of
TQM, 14 points of total
quality management, right?
You don't need to know what those 14
points are, you just need to know that he
is the one that developed those 14 points
of TQM, total quality management.
And we also mentioned him in an early
video as well, well, when we talked about
the PDCA cycle, if you remember,
the Plan Do Check Act cycle.
Now, amongst these 14 points, He also
observed that it's actually management
that contribute to the cost of poor
quality 85% of the time.
The worker contributes to cost of poor
quality only 15% of the time.
Of course, you know, management is going
to blame the worker 100% of the time.
And so he wasn't very popular
when he came out with this,
but this was one of his
defining moments, if you like.
There's one of his major observations.
It's actually management.
Management are the
one that put the quality
management processes
and procedures in place.
The worker just follows those procedures.
And then together with Shuart,
they came up with a PDCA cycle,
or rather it was Shuart, Walter Shuart
that came up with a PDCA cycle,
Plan Do Check Act cycle, and Deming really
took it, modified it,
and really promoted it.
And here was the one that also defined the
special cause, common cause variation that
we talked about in the control chart
section.
Then you have this guy called Toguchi,
Toguchi's loss function, and he's
basically establishing users dissatisfaction
based on a financial measure.
Again, you don't need to know,
I hope, you know, any more details.
And then Kano model, right, so by this guy
called Noriyaki Kano, and he basically
tracks what's actually a customer versus
what delights a customer versus what
dissatisfies a customer and you know we
mentioned the cana model in an earlier
video as well um this basically goes uh to
or refers also to the must have should
have remember the Moscow must have should
have could have won't have so what
satisfies a customer what dissatisfies a
customer if their feature isn't there this
is a must have you absolutely have to have
this otherwise the um a customer is not
going to be happy So that's kind of like
what the Canaan model refers to.
Again, you don't need to know any of these
in a huge amount of detail.
You just need to be aware.
I'm really enough to be able to answer a
PMP exam question.
So these are just some
of the important quality
theorists that you need to
be aware of for the PNP exam.